Uzair Akhtar

118 Rutland Road, West Bridgford, Nottingham, NG2 5DR Email: <u>uzair1200@hotmail.co.uk</u>, Mobile: +44 7852344108

Professional Profile

An ambitious and committed Electronic Engineering and Computer Science graduate with a sound understanding of electronics and programming as well a great deal of practical experience gained through university. With excellent planning and teamwork skills due to taking on many individual and team-based university projects, I now seek to explore the opportunities available in the technology industry.

Education and Qualifications

2018-2022 Aston University

BEng Electronic Engineering and Computer Science

Grade: First Class Honours

- IET accredited degree.
- First year modules: Digital and Analogue Electronics, Java Programming Development, Electronic System Design, Core Engineering Mathematics, and Electrical Circuit Theory.
- Second year modules: Data Structures & Algorithms with Java, Software Engineering, and System Modelling & Computer Control.
- Final year modules: Software Project Management, Information Security, Data mining, Internet of Things, and Testing & Reliable Software Engineering.
- Gained a strong understanding in digital and analogue electronics, as well as the ability to plan and design circuits.
- Developed knowledge on using various programming platforms to execute a given task and became familiar with different programming languages.
- Member of the Aston Electronics Society and Aston Computer Science Society.

2016-2018 Rushcliffe Sixth Form

3 A-Levels: Physics (C), Maths (C) and Chemistry (C)

2011-2016 Rushcliffe School

9 GCSEs (grade A-C) including English and Maths.

Employment History

June 2022 - September 2022 Tech Trainee, Futureproof

- 13-week bootcamp covering the main areas of web development, including JavaScript, HTML/CSS, Databases, and Python.
- Completed a variety of different projects such as a 1-week group project using React to create a trivia quiz and using Jest and Enzyme to test.

September 2020 - July 2021 Transport Escort, Special Educational Needs

- Current full-time role working as a transport escort which involves supervising special needs pupils whilst they are transported from home to school/college and vice versa.
- > Gained proficient communication skills by ensuring the safety of passengers.
- > Gained excellent time-management skills by following a set weekly rota which could change at short notice.
- ➤ Worked with special needs students in an age rage of 11-23 which shows my ability to work with multiple age ranges.

August 2019 - March 2020 Grocery Assistant, ASDA

- Part time role working as a grocery assistant which involves replenishing stock, assisting customers and handling checkout.
- > Developed excellent customer service skills and learnt to be confident when communicating with customers.
- Learnt to work as part of a team to achieve goals quicker and to be more organised and time efficient when working to meet targets.

- > Full UK driving license
- > Strong written and verbal communication skills
- Competent use of Microsoft Office applications
- Able to program in multiple programming languages such as Java and Python
- > Familiar with multiple programming software including Blue J, Eclipse, IntelliJ, Atmel Studio, and Arduino
- Knowledge of HTML, CSS, and JavaScript
- Proficient at schematic capture and PCB design in Proteus Software and the ability to solder
- Working knowledge of VHDL
- Proficient in using MATLAB

University Projects

Audio Amplifier PCB

- > This project was to design an audio amplifier for a speaker with a specific set of requirements which would take a signal from an MP3 player in order to amplify it and drive a speaker.
- Actions taken in this project included creating a schematic design of the circuit which required building each stage of the circuit in steps to creating a PCB and soldering on the necessary components.
- The result achieved was a working PCB amplifier which took a signal from the device I had chosen and amplified it to give the correct requirements set (e.g. the correct gain).
- > For further development I would work on the neatness of my final PCB design for example by using less solder and placing components closer together on the board.

Java Team Project

- This project involved working in a team of four students to design a robot grid-based board game in Eclipse to allow players to race their robot to touch all the flags that had been setup across the board in a specific order.
- The criteria of this project included programming the robots to have a sequence of 5 different actions that can be performed e.g. move one space forward or move one space back, operating the robots in player order, and having the winner being the first player to touch all the flags.
- My main responsibilities in this project included designing different location types for the board, for example pits across the board which would destroy robots that landed on them as well as implementing test classes using JUnit to test important aspects of the functionality of the system.
- Throughout this project, I developed key skills such as how to communicate effectively in a team and how to work together to come up with the best solution.

Other / Personal Details

Interests:

- Member of the Aston Electronics Society where I have full access to equipment and resources to work on projects in my spare time.
- Physically active and visit the gym frequently.
- A keen interest in several sports such as football where I have been part of many teams in the past.

REFERENCES ARE AVAILABLE ON REQUEST